Ian C. Denard

1531 S. 10th St., #1, Philadelphia, PA 19147

Phone: 303-507-6725 Email: ian.denard@gmail.com

Summary

Professional with a strong work ethic and the ability to lead and problem solve with resourcefulness; including but not limited to 5 years of personnel management, 3 years classroom planning/instruction/management, 2 years of curriculum design, thinking outside-the-box and a demonstrated history of getting results.

Experience

String Theory Schools

2014-Present

7th Grade ELA Teacher

Responsible for all aspects of curriculum creation, planning and delivery, classroom management, and contact with parents. In addition to these duties, it is imperative to have a full understanding of the latest trends in technology, as iPad deployment has supplemented textbooks.

- Design and implement curriculum from the ground up, create lessons and deliver the English Language Arts in new and innovate ways through the use of technology and iTunes U.
- Manage the participation, behavior, and work of all students assigned to my class.
- Stay abreast on new innovations in technology in order to remain relevant.

Cherry Creek School District

2013-2014

Substitute Teacher/Summer School

Execute lesson plans according to specification and ensure students get quality education while in the classroom.

- Implement lesson plans.
- Tailor lessons to work for exceptional individuals.
- Manage all aspects of the students assigned to my classroom.

Student Teacher

Horizon Middle School

- Student teacher under Mr. Jared Ortiz-Gray, Fall 2013
- Executed lesson plans and classroom management under the guidance of Mr. Ortiz-Gray, as well as college supervisor Mr. Woodie Smith.

TAG Burger Bar - Denver, CO

2011-2014

Floor Manager

Ensure a positive guest experience at all times, create schedules for staff, handle financials at the end of each shift, maintain a productive and positive work environment.

Comcast Corporation

2007-2011

National Account Support Representative II - Centennial, CO

Managed high speed internet accounts, both billing and technical, for teleworker employees of major corporations. During this time I also worked with the Comcast Credo Action Team in efforts to improve employee life, as well as better business practices.

Communication Technician III - Denver, CO

Install and repair television, internet, and voice services in customers home, always ensuring white-glove service and guaranteeing the work to be above the expectations of the customer.

United States Marine Corps Reserve, Corporal

1996-2002

Air Traffic Control Communications Technician

Education

Metropolitan State University of Denver, *Denver, CO*Post-baccalaurate Teacher Licensure in Language Arts, Grades 7-12

E. Stroudsburg University, E. Stroudsburg, PA B.A. in Sociology

Awards & Honors

Professional Learning Community, String Theory Schools

Co-presenter at CLAS Conference '11

Writing Coach for Freshman students at Metro State

Personal Skills

Curriculum design, Lesson planning/implementation, Educational Technology, Technology implementation, Classroom management, Personnel management, Resource management, Detail oriented, Windows proficiency, Mac proficiency